(vocalizing)
(tense music playing)
(water flowing)
(indistinct yelling)
(winces, groans)
(people yelling)
(distant screaming)
King Viserys: Ser Ryam was a strong
Lord Commander
of the Kingsguard.
But he was ill for some time.
He passed in peace, I hope.
Grand Maester Mellos: Yes, Your Grace.
He was found to have passed
gently in his sleep.
His remains are being prepared
by the Silent Sisters.
The succeeding Lord Commander,
Ser Harrold,
would like to make
haste in finding
Ser Ryam's replacement
on the Kingsguard.
Ser Harrold Westerling: Your Grace. My lords.
The Kingsguard must soon be restored
to its full complement of seven.
With the help of the Hand,
I've invited a number of
fine candidates to court.
All have passed fair trials.
(door opens)
Four ships have now been lost.
The last one was
flying my banner.
The Stepstones have now
grown into a conflagration,
yet you sit here
and dither about court business.
Ser Otto Hightower: If you've something to discuss,
Lord Corlys...
I want to know
what is to be done
about my ships and my men.
The Crown will compensate you
for your ship and crew,
and make an offering
- to the men's families.
- I don't want compensation.
I want to seize
the Stepstones by force
and burn out this Crabfeeder.
I am not prepared to start
a war with the Free Cities.
These pirates are
not the Free Cities.
Who do you think provides them
with their ships and tender?
In all of its history, my lord,
the Seven Kingdoms
have never entered
open war with the Free Cities.
Were that to happen,
the losses would
be incalculable.
What reason does
the Crabfeeder have to fear us?
The King's own brother has been allowed
to seize Dragonstone
and fortify it with an army
of his gold cloaks.
Daemon has squatted there
for over half a year
without even a protest
from The Crown.
I'll caution you, Lord Corlys,
a seat at the King's table
does not make you his equal.
I have acted, Corlys.
I've sent envoys
to Pentos and Volantis
to see if we might
find common cause.
Ships and men are at the ready.
The Stepstones
will be settled... in time.
You have dragonriders, father.
Send us.
(soft chuckle)
It isn't that simple,
Rhaenyra.
It would be a show of force.
At least the Princess
has a plan.
- I only meant that we should at least...
- Otto: Perhaps, uh...
there's some better use
for the Princess's talents, Your Grace.
King Viserys: Why don't you take
the Princess to see about the new
Kingsguard posting,
Lord Commander?
A fine idea, Your Grace.
This knight will
protect you as well.
You should choose.
(scoffs)
(door opens)
(birds chirping)
Harrold: Ser Desmond Caron,
a fine knight, Princess.
Step forward, Ser Desmond.
Son of Ser Royce Caron,
Ser Desmond has proved
strong and steady
in both the tourney lists
and without.
While traveling through the Kingswood
on his way to King's Landing,
Ser Desmond recently brought
a would-be poacher
to justice.
You might thank him
for his leal service, Princess.
We thank you for your loyal
service to The Crown, ser.
(footsteps departing)
Harrold: Ser Rymun Mallister.
Son of Lord Lymond Mallister
of Seagard.
Winner of the melee
at Cider Hall.
He was the last mounted
of three-and-twenty knights.
Ser Rymun was knighted
at eight-and-ten.
Do any of these knights
have combat experience?
Beyond capturing poachers.
(city bells tolling)
Harrold: Ser Criston Cole.
Son of the steward
of the Lord of Blackhaven.
Be welcome, Ser Criston.
You saw combat
in the Stormlands.
Dornish marches, Princess.
I fought for a year as a foot solider
against the Dornish incursions.
Ser Arlan Dondarrion
knighted me after we razed
two of the watchtowers
along the Boneway.
I choose Ser Criston Cole.
Let's not be too hasty,
Princess.
There's no doubt Ser Criston
is a fine warrior,
but houses such as
Crakehall and Mallister
are important allies
of The Crown.
Seagard, for instance,
is the realm's prime defense
against reavers
from the Iron Islands.
Those men are tourney knights.
My father should be defended by a man
who's known real combat.
Should he not?
Of course, Princess.
Well, let us plan Ser Criston's
investiture then.
(city bells tolling)
King Viserys: The Valyrian capital
was built into a volcano,
much like Dragonstone.
And the dragonlords,
the highest of the nobility,
lived here,
at the volcanic face,
closest to the source
of their magic and power.
And this was the Anogrion.
Where the bloodmages
worked their craft.
It is truly wondrous
what you've built.
Oh no.
I only pore over the histories
and provide the plans.
The stonemasons
built the structures.
Do you believe that Westeros
can be another Valyria,
Your Grace?
That depends,
whether you speak
of the Freehold
at its height or at its fall.
Over a thousand dragons,
a navy large enough to span
the seas of the world.
The glory of Old Valyria
will never be seen again.
(object breaks)
Seven Hells.
(birds cawing)
Tell me, how is Rhaenyra?
- What do you mean?
- Well, these days,
she doesn't say more
than a few words to me.
I think she might
find it difficult...
to discuss personal matters.
It will take time.
It did when I lost
mine own mother.
I wish she would approach me.
What if you went to her?
There are times when
I would rather face
the Black Dread himself
than mine own daughter of 15.
(chuckles)
I think she would open
herself to you if invited.
You do have such an easy way about you,
Your Grace.
Um...
you do not mention our talks to Rhaenyra,
do you?
I just...
I fear that she wouldn't
understand them.
No, Your Grace.
(seabirds cawing)
It's only been half a year
since my mother died,
and already they tried
to marry my father off
and replace me as heir.
I know those men
and how they plot
in their secret councils
when I've been sent away.
You cannot worry at the matters
of lords and kings, Rhaenyra.
What if your father
were to remarry?
Your father loves you.
He chose you for his heir.
He didn't choose me.
He spurns Daemon.
Kneel with me.
I find this is a way
to be with my mother.
Here in the quiet
of the Sept...
I feel close to her.
- I know it sounds foolish.
- I don't think it's foolish.
- I don't.
- Good...
because I thought you might try.
I...
If not for me, then,
perhaps for them.
(sighs)
What do I say?
Whatever you wish.
It's only for you
and the gods to know.
(poignant music playing)
(crying)
I want him to see me as
more than his little girl.
Mine own father does not know
the language of girls either.
(Rhaenyra chuckles)
When I wish to talk with him...
I know that I must
make the effort.
Thank you.
Corlys Velaryon: Your Grace.
King Viserys: I'm glad we could meet.
I know tempers ran hot today,
and I wanted to assure you
how much I value the bond
between our houses.
Rhaenys is my favorite
cousin after all.
I wish to apologize
for the tenor
at the Small Council today,
Your Grace.
It was not my intent
to make offense.
Your fleet is one of the realm's
most important assets,
Lord Corlys.
But you must understand,
as King, it is my
obligation to avoid war
until such time
it is unavoidable.
None among us desire open war.
Might I speak plainly,
Your Grace?
I always welcome the unfettered thoughts
of my council.
I fear that the eyes
of our enemies
are presently fixed
on the Red Keep.
The Queen has passed.
A girl has been named
heir to the Iron Throne,
the first in its history.
The King's brother,
so disinherited,
has claimed the Targaryen seat
on Dragonstone
without challenge.
And now, a foreign power
has established a colony
in our most critical
shipping lane.
You paint such an aspirant portrait
of my reign, Lord Corlys.
It is an honest one, cousin.
At the moment, The Crown is perceived
as being vulnerable.
And a blind incursion
in the Stepstones
is the only way to demonstrate
that we are not?
Corlys: To elude a storm,
you can either sail into it
or around it.
But you must never
await its coming.
Do you have a specific
course of action to propose,
my lord?
Join our families.
Wed our daughter, Laena.
Unite the two great surviving
Valyrian houses.
With the Targaryen dragons
and the Velaryon fleet
bound in blood,
you can show the realm
that The Crown's strongest days
are ahead...
not behind.
(tense music playing)
I must admit...
I haven't given
marriage much thought.
It hasn't even been half a year
since Aemma passed.
The realm expects you
to take a new wife
soon or late, Your Grace,
to strengthen your line
and produce more heirs.
You could not ask for
a stronger match than Laena.
(crickets chirping)
We haven't spoken much...
since.
A regret of mine.
We should be free to speak our minds
to one another.
You can say whatever
you'd like.
You are the King.
(chuckles)
I loved your mother...
very much.
As did I.
(tapping on table)
(sighs)
Ser Harrold provided a fine
field of tourney knights.
Oh?
But in questioning them,
I discovered that Ser Criston
was the only man among them
with true battle experience.
(chuckles)
He'll make a fine
knight of the Kingsguard.
- Today at Small Council...
- Pay it no mind.
- I, I thought I might have had some insight, but...
- You're young.
You will learn.
Mellos: This is our best chance
to save the digit, Your Grace.
The maggots will
remove the dead flesh
and hopefully stop
the advance of the rot.
I held an audience
earlier today
with Lord Corlys
and Princess Rhaenys.
That was most charitable
of you, Your Grace.
I'm sure Lord Corlys
appreciated the spirit of it.
He proposed a marriage.
To whom, Your Grace?
The Lady Laena.
To combine the strength
of our houses,
and demonstrate my reign's
strongest days are ahead,
not behind.
Lord Corlys has
overreached, Your Grace.
Such matters must be discussed
with the Small Council.
That is what I'm doing,
presently.
So... what is your
advice, dear Otto.
Otto: The Lady Laena...
is young, Your Grace.
Indeed, but the wounds
made by the Great Council
still linger, my King.
A match with their daughter
would go a long way towards
sealing the breach
and uniting the two
great Valyrian houses
would certainly signal unity
throughout the realm
and beyond.
The Grand Maester's
reasoning is sound.
I do fear what
Rhaenyra might think.
Mellos: What does it matter,
Your Grace?
Her mother has passed.
Her father must propagate
the royal line.
I, uh, dearly loved
my own lady wife.
The pain of her passing
still haunts me.
And to be compelled to...
replace her for duty's sake.
You are the King.
But I do not envy you.
(birds chirping)
(insects buzzing)
What was it like
flying the Black Dread?
You were Balerion's
last rider.
Only for a short time
before he died.
With Balerion
died the last memory
of Valyria of Old.
But Vhagar still lives...
somewhere.
(King Viserys sighs)
Bit too large
for the Dragonpit.
Some would say too
large for our world.
- Do you know where she nests?
- I'm sorry?
Do you know where Vhagar is now?
Um, the Dragonkeepers
believe she made home
somewhere on the coast
of the Narrow Sea.
The workers at Spicetown report
hearing her song at times.
They say it is a sad thing.
(King Viserys sighs)
I imagine even
dragons get lonely.
Your Grace...
it would be a great honor
to join our houses
as they were in Old Valyria.
I would give you many children
of pure Valyrian blood
so that we might strengthen
the royal line
and the realm.
Is that what your father
told you to say?
What did your mother tell you?
That I wouldn't have to bed you
until I turned 14.
(sighs)
(pensive music playing)
It bothers you, does it not?
My father is a king.
It is his duty
to take a new wife
and strengthen his line.
I did not ask for
a lesson in politics.
I asked whether
this bothers you.
Laena is your daughter,
Princess.
Does it bother you?
Of course, it does.
But I understand
the order of things.
I'm not sure you do.
If you mean to elicit
some anger from me,
you should know that
you're failing, Princess.
Quite the opposite.
Whether it's to my daughter
or to someone else's,
your father will remarry
sooner than late.
His new wife will
produce new heirs,
and chances are better than not
that one of those will be male.
And when that boy comes of age
and your father has passed,
the men of the realm
will expect him to be heir,
not you.
Because that is
the order of things.
When I'm Queen,
I will create a new order.
(Princess Rhaenys chuckles)
How I wish that could be,
Rhaenyra.
But the men of the realm
already had their opportunity
to appoint a ruling queen
at the Great Council
and they denied it.
They denied you,
Princess Rhaenys.
"The Queen Who Never Was."
But they bent the knee to me
and called me
heir to the throne.
Do you remind your
father's men of that
as you carry their cups?
Here is the hard truth,
which no one else has
the heart to tell you.
Men would sooner put
the realm to the torch
than see a woman
ascend the Iron Throne.
(tense music playing)
And your father is no fool.
King Viserys: The Small Council is
urging me to remarry.
It seems the realm
wants for a new queen.
A good and kind queen
will give comfort to your subjects.
- Does the Small Council have a particular lady in mind?
- Uh...
Lord Corlys Velaryon has offered
the hand of his daughter,
the Lady Laena.
A very strong match, Your Grace.
I must admit, I,
I don't know Laena very well.
I'm sure that she
is good and kind,
and that she will enjoy your company,
as I have, Your Grace.
I brought you something.
I asked the stonemasons
to mend it.
(chuckles)
This is, um,
a very kind gesture, Alicent.
Very kind.
(knocking on door)
Come.
(door opens)
Harrold: The Hand, Your Grace.
(door closes)
Your Grace, I've called
the Small Council
to an emergency session.
Why?
I think it best
you hear it directly.
Very well.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(speaking High Valyrian)
- Daemon.
- The Prince left a missive,
which I believe might explain.
"It is the pleasure
of Daemon Targaryen,
"the Prince of Dragonstone
"and rightful heir
to the Iron Throne,
"to announce that he is
to take a second wife
"in the tradition
of Old Valyria.
"She is to assume the title
Lady Mysaria of Dragonstone.
"Her Grace is with child
"and is to have a dragon's egg
placed in the babe's cradle
in the custom
of House Targaryen."
The Prince has invited you
to his wedding, Your Grace.
- It is in two days' time.
- Gods be good.
Who is Lady Mysaria?
- Mellos: We believe...
- Otto: Daemon's whore.
- This is nothing less than sedition.
- I strongly agree, sire.
My brother wishes to provoke me.
To answer is to give
him what he wants.
The realm is watching,
Your Grace.
King Viserys: What would you have me do?
Send him to the Wall?
Perhaps I could put
his head on a spike.
Otto: Daemon has seized Dragonstone,
has surrounded himself
with an army of gold cloaks,
and has now stolen
a dangerous weapon...
(speaking High Valyrian)
Assemble a detachment, Otto.
I will go to Dragonstone
and drag Daemon back
- to face justice myself.
- Otto: Your Grace.
My apologies, Your Grace,
but I cannot allow it.
It's too dangerous.
Daemon is without limit.
Let me go to Dragonstone.
(pensive music playing)
(Otto sighs)
You're the most
comely girl at court.
Why do you destroy yourself?
Hm?
Will you see the King tonight?
If you wish it.
- Good day, Ser Criston.
- My Lady.
I've assembled 20 of your best
household guards, my Lord Hand.
Sir Harrold will also join us.
(tense music playing)
Alicent: Please look after
the Hand, Ser Criston.
(waves crashing)
(footsteps approaching)
Welcome to Dragonstone, Otto.
Otto: Your occupation of this
island is at an end.
You're to relinquish
the dragon's egg,
disband your army,
banish your whore...
and leave Dragonstone
by order of His Grace,
- King Viserys...
- Where is the King? I don't see him.
His Grace would never lower himself
to entertain such a mummer's farce.
Ser Crispin, wasn't it?
Ser Criston Cole: Ser Criston Cole, my Prince.
Ah, yes, apologies.
I couldn't recall.
Perhaps my Prince recalls when
I knocked him off his horse.
(chuckles) Very good.
Otto: This is a truly
pathetic show, Daemon.
Are you so desperate
for the King's attention
that you've resorted
to skulking about
- like a common cutpurse?
- I'm simply keeping
with the traditions of my house,
the same as my brother
did for his heir.
Those traditions are for the trueborn
children of royalty,
not for bastards fathered
on a common whore.
Lady Mysaria is to be my wife.
Otto: This is an abomination.
With every breath
you soil your name,
your house,
and your brother's reign.
Our love does not know
titles and traditions.
And what of you,
men of the City Watch?
Aiding the Prince
in his treason?
Prince Daemon: The King made me
their commander.
They are loyal to me.
You've come for the egg.
Here it is.
Are you mad?
- You'd never survive this.
- Well, happily, neither would you.
To choose violence, here,
is to declare war against your King.
Wonderful.
Even if it ends in the death
of your unborn child
and its mother?
(rumbling)
(Caraxes screeching)
(screeching)
(roars)
(Caraxes grumbling)
All of you...
sheathe the fucking steel.
(distant dragon rumbling)
(wings flapping)
(Syrax screeching)
(roars)
(dragons screeching)
- What are you doing here, Princess?
- Preventing bloodshed.
Ser Criston, please escort
the Princess to safety.
Take care not to startle Syrax,
my lords.
She's rather protective of me.
(speaking High Valyrian)
(waves crashing)
I'm right here, Uncle...
the object of your ire...
the reason that you
were disinherited.
If you wish to be
restored as heir,
you'll need to kill me.
So, do it.
And be done
with all this bother.
(footsteps departing)
(intense music playing)
(vocalizing)
(Syrax screeches)
(grumbles, roars)
(triumphant music swells)
(wind blowing)
(metal clinking)
(Prince Daemon sighs)
Lady Mysaria: You announced that
we were to be wed?
On the morrow.
And that I was with child.
Your child.
Well, perhaps when we are wed,
we can make that true.
I ensured long ago
that I would never be
threatened by childbirth.
Good. Children can be such
irritating creatures.
You swore to protect me,
Daemon.
Dragonstone is quite secure.
Until the King decides to reclaim
his ancestral seat.
His men might not put
the Prince's head on a spike,
but what would they do
with the common whore
he claims he's taken to wife
and made with child?
No one will harm you.
I have been sold as property
more times than I care to count,
beginning in a homeland
I can no longer recall.
Most of my years have been spent
living in terror.
You're safe with me, I swear it.
You are Targaryen.
You can afford to play
your stupid games with the King,
but I cannot.
I didn't come into your service
wanting gold or power
or station.
- I came to you to be liberated.
- Liberated.
From what?
Fear.
(pensive music playing)
(door closes)
No, please, Lord Lyonel.
I have come looking for
an unencumbered opinion.
That's all I would
ever give, Your Grace.
Ever since my name was read
by the archmaesters at the Great Council,
I have felt Corlys Velaryon's
envious gaze staring at me
from across the Blackwater.
You sit upon the highest seat
in the realm, Your Grace.
Proud men don't like
having to look up.
Laena Velaryon.
Lord Corlys is your
Master of Ships
and she is the eldest daughter
of the wealthiest
house in the realm.
She comes from unimpeachable
Velaryon stock
and she has Targaryen blood.
- What's to mislike?
- She is 12.
She will mature.
I never asked to remarry.
As King, you have a claim
on all things.
Even those you don't want.
Marriage is not an obligation
you can put off for long.
What if I was to reject
Lord Corlys's proposal?
He would not be like
to take it well.
I fear nothing short
of a direct line
to the Iron Throne
would satisfy him.
You should also consider
that we find ourselves
on the precipice of war
in the Stepstones.
And the Sea Snake holds claim to nearly
half the realm's ships.
He would not dare withhold them
in the face of the realm's need.
- Who is he to hector me?
- No one, Your Grace.
But Driftmark makes
for a better ally
than it does an enemy.
The Sea Snake has made
a calculated reach,
a fair play for a man
of his position.
- If you truly want my unencumbered opinion...
- I do.
You should wed Laena Velaryon,
Your Grace.
Sate Lord Corlys
and fix him at your side,
permanently, as an ally.
(door opens)
Ser Steffon Darklyn: Your Grace,
the Princess has returned
from Dragonstone.
Dragonstone?
(tense music playing)
(vocalizing)
Your Grace.
King Viserys: You disobeyed me.
You fled King's Landing
without a word
and you acted without
The Crown's leave.
You are my only heir.
You could've been killed.
May I sit?
You went to Dragonstone.
And retrieved the egg
without bloodshed.
A feat I'm not sure Ser Otto
could've accomplished alone.
Yes, well...
(chuckles)
I sometimes forget
how alike you both were.
(sighs)
Your mother's absence
is a wound that will never heal.
Without her...
the Red Keep has lost a warmth
that I dare say
it will never recover.
It pleases me
to hear you say this.
To know that I'm not alone
in my grief.
I wish I had known better
what to say to you
in the aftermath.
I struggled to realize that my daughter
had so quickly become a woman grown.
But I know...
she understands what
is now expected of me.
The King must take a new wife.
I could never
replace your mother.
No more than I intend
to replace you as heir.
But you are my only heir
and our line is vulnerable,
too easily ended.
And by marrying again,
I may begin to ensure
- that we are better defended.
- Against whom?
Whomever may dare
to challenge us.
I do not wish
to make us estranged.
You are the King...
and so, your first duty
is to the realm.
Mother would've understood this.
Just as I do.
(bell tolls)
(birds cawing)
(pensive music playing)
(door opens)
(indistinct chatter)
(door closes)
Good morrow, my lords.
I have decided
to take a new wife.
I intend to marry...
the Lady Alicent Hightower
before spring's end.
This is an absurdity.
My house is Valyrian,
the greatest power in the realm.
And I am your King.
(tense music playing)
(door opens)
(door closes)
King Viserys: Rhaenyra.
(door opens)
House Velaryon's origins
reach back to Old Valyria.
More ancient even than
House Targaryen...
according to some texts.
But unlike the Targaryens,
we were no dragonlords.
For centuries, my house had to scratch out
an existence from the sea
with grit and luck.
When I ascended
the Driftwood Throne...
I knew what I wanted.
So I went out and seized it.
Unlike every other
lord of the realm,
I can say that I built
my house's high seat
with the strength
of mine own back.
(tense music playing)
I've always thought of
you and I as having been
made from the same cloth.
I wasn't aware you had
a king for a brother.
We're both men
who have had to cut
our own way through the world.
We've been passed over...
too often.
Did you call me to Driftmark
to remind me of my
low standing, Lord Corlys,
or was there some other reason?
You've heard of the troubles
in the Stepstones?
Daemon: Some Myrish Prince
is feeding Westerosi
sailors to the crabs.
Corlys: I have been petitioning
the King to send my navy
into the territory,
but he's denied me.
- It was never my brother's strongest trait.
- What?
Being King.
Corlys: The Crabfeeder is backed
by powerful entities
within the Free Cities who wish to see
Westeros weakened.
(sailor grunting)
And the King's failures
have allowed him
to accumulate strength.
If those shipping lanes fall,
my house will be crippled.
And I will not have Driftmark
beggared while our King
idles himself with feasts
and balls and tourneys.
I will speak of
my brother as I wish.
You will not.
Waiting in the Stepstones
is a chance for you
to prove your worth
to any who might yet doubt it.
We are the realm's
second sons, Daemon.
Our worth is not given.
It must be made.
(intense music playing)