(EPIC THEME PLAYING)
PRINCESS RHAENYS: It's been near six years
since I last saw
my lord husband, Maester.
I must know... will he live?
MAESTER KELVYN: He led his sailors
into an ambush.
A ship made to look
as if it were abandoned.
In the fighting,
his neck was slashed by a corsair's dagger.
He fell overboard into the sea.
The wound was severe.
Much blood was lost.
But the greater concern
is the fever that followed.
The ship's maester said
he burns from within.
(SEABIRDS CALLING)
The ravens came in from?
KELVYN: Even fall, Princess.
So they arrive in three days.
Let all be made ready
to receive him, Maester Kelvyn.
The Sea Snake is strong.
VAEMOND VELARYON: No doubt.
And yet, I have seen
blood fever overcome men half his age.
I will not suffer the talk
of crows in my house, Vaemond.
I love my brother...
but we must be honest
with ourselves.
We may greet his ship
to find him gone.
And who will take
the Driftwood Throne?
My grandmother seems
quite comfortable here.
She presides
only in the absence of her husband.
On his death, the seat passes.
To Lucerys Velaryon.
As is my lord husband's desire.
I am the Sea Snake's own blood,
the closest kin he has left.
Be careful, good-brother.
One could take
your words for treason.
I speak the truth, Rhaenys.
And you know it.
The matter has been decided.
VAEMOND: By a man whose ambition
has brought down on us
calamity after calamity.
My brother cares only
for the history books.
But what of the Velaryon line?
Is it to be snuffed out,
supplanted by the pups
of House Strong?
Driftmark is mine by all rights.
And while I should
like your support,
I do not... need it.
The winds have shifted.
The crown has good reason...
to take my side.
My cousin the King would
have your tongue for this.
But it's not a king who sits
the Iron Throne these days, good-sister.
It's a queen.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(HISSING)
(SPEAKING HIGH VALYRIAN)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
PRINCE JACAERYS: The Conqueror
and his sisters
sailed with a great army.
MAESTER GERARDYS: (SPEAKING HIGH VALYRIAN)
Se Blakuata Rasho
dranot vilinio viartis.
JACAERYS: (EXHALES) And
landed at the Blackwater Rush.
Dr a not.
JACAERYS: Dr a not.
At the end?
- The mouth.
- Mouth! Ah, come on, Jace, you knew that.
Dr a not.
- Dr a not vilinio viartis.
- Dr a not.
Dr a not.
Come on, Jace.
Perhaps that's enough
for this morning.
No, no.
I-I want to keep going.
- Maester.
- Guesi misenakson Aegon undas.
Aegon... ordered
that the trees should be...
- ...killed.
- PRINCESS RHAENYRA: Felled.
It is a related word.
I don't expect you
to learn High Valyrian in a day, Jace.
A king should honor
the traditions of his forbears.
Well... unless you're planning
to depose your own mother,
you have plenty
of time to study.
(DOOR OPENS)
Leave us.
Joffrey... come.
He means to call
into question Luke's legitimacy.
And by extension Jace,
and by extension
my own claim to the throne.
Vaemond cares only
about Driftmark
and the Velaryon line.
Not about our politics.
Has he made common cause
with Otto High tower yet?
Hm, this is what I fear.
Rhaenys has flown to court.
- Surely, she cannot be planning to back him.
- No.
Whatever disagreements
we may have had,
she's not cruel...
- or stupid enough to do that.
- Disagreements?
She believes we had her son
killed so that we might marry.
Yes... and yet,
she's taken Baela to ward.
Yes. It is Laena's
memory she honors. She has no love for us.
Has the vipers' venom
spread so far?
Those vipers rule
in my father's name.
And my father...
(SIGHS)
What choice do I have?
(RHAENYRA SIGHS)
To King's Landing, then.
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRDS CAWING)
STEFFON DARKLYN: All hail
Rhaenyra of House Targaryen,
Princess of Dragons tone
and heir to the Iron Throne
and her royal consort,
Prince Daemon Targaryen.
(BELLS TOLLING)
Welcome back, Princess.
Lord Caswell.
I would say it's
nice to be home,
- but I scarcely recognize it.
- PRINCE DAEMON: Mm.
LYMAN BEESBURY: We have continued
to enjoy improved customs duties
since the settling
of the Step stones.
And the extent to
which we exploit those
is contingent on
the harbor master's receipts.
Of which, um, uh,
the, uh, septons have requested
half that again
for a bronze bust
they wish to co... to commission
for the, the Festival
of the Mother,
which I would not recommend.
Thank you for that exhaustive
accounting, Lord Beesbury.
I remind you...
Your guests have arrived,
Your Grace.
I trust they've been welcomed
as befits their station.
As you instructed, Lord Hand.
GRAND MAESTER ORWYLE: It was
my understanding Lord Corlys wished
for his grandson Lucerys
to succeed him
as Lord of the Tides.
The boy has been raised
most of his life away from Driftmark.
He can fly a dragon, yes,
but can he command a fleet?
Ability does not
alter his claim.
The Sea Snake has never
formally named him as heir,
if it comes to that.
The crown must choose
what is best for the realm.
He is Laenor's son.
What grounds could there be...
What indeed, Lord Beesbury.
What indeed.
We shall hear
Princess Rhaenyra's petition,
along with those
of the other claimants on the morrow.
- But...
- I do beg your pardon, my lords.
I must greet our guests.
Shall we levy a tax
on the sale of new wool?
Your Grace...
a matter has arisen that
requires your attention.
Whatever it is, Ser Arryk,
it'll need to wait.
- I'm Erryk, Your Grace.
- Of course. My apologies, ser.
It's about the Prince.
There's been
a delicate situation in his apartments.
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
- Father?
- (WHEEZING BREATHS)
(WHEEZING)
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING)
- Who goes there?
- RHAENYRA: Father.
It's me, my King.
Rhaenyra.
King Viserys: Oh...
Oh.
I'm here with Daemon.
(EXHALES) Daemon?
Daemon?
(EXHALES) Daemon.
(VISERYS WHEEZES)
Help me up.
(GROANING)
Oh...
(LABORED BREATHING)
(EXHALES)
It has been so long.
The Sea Snake has taken
a grave wound in battle in the Step stones.
When?
We won that war years ago.
No.
The Triarchy is resurgent.
The fighting is anew.
And there is a p... There is a petition to
decide upon the succession of Driftmark
and the heir
to the Driftwood Throne.
(VISERYS SIGHS)
VISERYS: Petitions?
Alicent and Otto...
they see to all that business now.
No, brother, listen to me.
You are to affirm
your position for Lucerys
to be Corlys Velaryon's
successor.
(DOOR OPENS)
Has something happened
to Lord Corlys?
(BABY BABBLING)
Father...
there's someone we wish
to introduce you to.
(LABORED BREATHING)
(BABBLING CONTINUES)
(SIGHS)
Daemon.
- Brother.
- (BABY BABBLES)
Who is that?
RHAENYRA: Father...
this is Aegon.
Aegon.
(EXHALES)
And this... is Viserys.
Ah... Viserys.
Oh.
(LAUGHS)
Now that is a name fit for a king.
(LAUGHING)
Oh...
Oh, oh...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm sorry. I-I'm sorry.
- (CHILDREN CRYING)
- I'm so...
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sor...
Please.
(MOUTHING)
- My tea... My tea.
- What tea? This?
Yes. Yes.
Yes.
(CHILDREN CRYING)
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(VISERYS SIGHS)
(SERVANT CRYING)
TALYA: I brought her here immediately.
She's seen no one else,
Your Grace.
- Come here, sweetling.
- (CRYING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Tell me your name.
It's Dyana, Your Grace.
If... i-if it please you.
Dyana. What a pretty name.
I understand you've found
yourself in some trouble.
I was fetching
the Prince his wine,
and I put it on his table,
and when I turned...
I didn't see him.
I asked him to stop, Your Grace.
I did, truly...
you must believe me.
(CRYING BREATHS)
Shh.
Thank you for telling me, Dyana.
- I know it wasn't your fault.
- Hm?
I believe you.
Y-You do?
I do.
But what I worry about...
is what others might believe.
You were alone with the Prince,
were you not?
Yes, I... (STAMMERS)
And no one else
saw what happened between the two of you.
If anyone else were
to hear about this...
- I haven't told anyone.
- You told Ser Erryk and Talya and now me.
And though I believe
you are not to blame,
others might not be so trusting.
They might think you were trying
to besmirch the Prince, or worse...
that you're the sort of girl that might
have enticed him in the first place.
And you know what happens
to girls like that.
I, I wouldn't dream of breathing
another word to anyone, Your Grace.
I, I swear it on my life.
(SHUDDERING BREATHS)
I know you won't.
For your troubles.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
The tea, Your Grace.
It's best to be certain.
(DYANA GULPS)
QUEEN ALICENT: Get up.
(SHOUTS) Aegon!
(YELLS) Get up!
(SIGHS) Mother?
- What is it?
- "What is it? What is it?"
What is it?"
That's all you can say for yourself?
Has something happened?
- Dyana.
- Mm?
ALICENT: The serving girl.
- (EXHALES)
- Oh, for the gods' sake.
The girl, Aegon.
The one you sent fleeing from your company.
PRINCE AEGON: (STRETCHING)
Oh, it was just harmless fun.
She didn't need to go
and get upset about it.
Think of the shame
on your wife, on me.
How can you keep
carrying on like this,
especially on a day like today?
Why? What is it today?
(SNIFFLES)
You are no son of mine.
I did not ask for this.
I've done everything
you've asked me to,
and I try so...
I try so hard, but it will never
be enough for you or father.
(DOOR OPENS)
Have you seen Dyana?
She's supposed to dress the children.
He looks like
a different person.
I believe we should also
consult Maester Gerardys.
Perhaps if he could see the
King, he'd suggest a different...
Princess Rhaenyra.
- And Prince Daemon.
- DAEMON: Hm.
It has been so long since we were
granted the joy of your presence.
Indeed, Your Grace.
Though not long enough
to merit a greeting upon our arrival.
I'm sure the Queen
had pressing business, my love.
What can either of us
know of ruling a kingdom?
I do not rule, as you well know.
My father and I are mere
stewards of the King's will and wisdom.
DAEMON: And how exactly
is that wisdom expressed...
hm?
In blinks and wheezes?
I'd be surprised
if he could remember his own name.
- Or if you could.
- King Viserys's condition
- has worsened since you saw him last.
- Hah.
It subjects him
to considerable pain.
- On the advice of the maesters...
- Ah, the maesters.
Of course.
It is they who keep him...
addled on milk of the poppy
while the High towers
warm his throne.
Rhaenyra, if you would
see him without it,
- almost blind with suffering.
- Oh, Alicent, I have no doubt
it was... an act
of the purest mercy,
but tell me,
for the King's suffering,
did the maesters also prescribe
the removal
of Targaryen heraldry
and the installation
in its stead of various statues and stars?
The emblems of the Seven serve
only to guide us on an uncertain path.
- To remind us of a higher authority.
- And on the morrow,
which authority will sit in judgment of
my son's claim on his own inheritance?
- That would be mine... and the Hand's.
- DAEMON: Ah.
But be assured,
the Father is just and commands me
to forget the accusations
you have hurled in this room today.
(SWORDS CLASHING)
- Smaller than I remember.
- It looks exactly the same.
- Ah, Luke, come on.
- (KNIGHTS, SQUIRES GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
See? I told you this
would still be here.
And you thought
you could swing Criston's morning star.
And you almost took
your own head off.
- What's your problem?
- Everyone's staring at us.
Hyah!
No one would question me
being heir to Driftmark...
if...
if I looked more like
Ser Laenor Velaryon than Ser Harwin Strong.
It doesn't matter
what they think.
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- (DISTANT GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
- (CROWD GASPS)
- Ooh.
(SWORD WHOOSHES)
(YELLING)
(CROWD APPLAUDS)
Well done, my Prince.
You'll be winning
tourneys in no time.
I don't give a shit
about tourneys.
Nephews...
have you come to train?
GUARD: (SHOUTS)
Open the gate!
(GATE OPENING)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(FOOTSTEPS MARCHING)
OTTO HIGH TOWER: Hold your nerve, my Queen.
What we do,
we do for the good of the realm.
I must confess
a certain uneasiness now this is at hand.
- He may yet live.
- But we must be prepared if he does not.
The realm has enjoyed
a long peace,
a credit to the work
of both Jaehaerys and Viserys,
but the threat of war looms
and may arrive on our shores.
When it does,
will you want a child at the command
of the greatest fleet
in Westeros?
We must, of course...
act in the interest
of our subjects.
The next Lord of the Tides
will be deeply in your debt, Your Grace.
As will Driftmark...
in all its strength.
(BELL TOLLING)
(THUNDERING)
RHAENA TARGARYEN: Grandmother?
Rhaena.
Baela said you might be here.
She's done well as your ward.
You've, um...
raised her admirably.
You honor me, Princess.
Might I speak to the Princess
alone, Rhaena?
Princess.
I wondered for many an hour
what your purpose
was in coming here.
Whether you'd speak for or against
the suit brought by Ser Vaemond.
But then, I realized...
you intend to advocate
for yourself.
This is no fair proceeding.
It is a trap
set by the Queen and the Hand,
I'd wager,
to proclaim my son illegitimate.
Yet you did worse
than that with Laenor.
Did you not?
I loved your son.
You may not believe it
to be true, but I did.
I did not order his death.
Nor was I complicit in it.
I swear this to you.
I'll make you an offer.
Back Luke's claim,
and let us betroth
Laena's children to mine.
Baela will be Queen
of the Seven Kingdoms
and her sons will be
heirs to the throne.
Rhaena will rule
in Driftmark, and...
the seat will pass
to her and Lucerys's children in time.
A generous offer.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
- Or a desperate one.
- What does it matter?
(SOFT CHUCKLE)
You are right in this, at least.
It does not matter.
You can bargain
with me all you like.
Bring my granddaughter
with you to soften my resolve.
But tomorrow,
the High towers land their first blow.
They force you to your knees...
and I must stand alone.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXHALES)
(THUNDERING, RAIN FALLING)
(LIGHTNING CRACKS)
(VISERYS BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOFTLY) Alicent?
Alicent...
No, it's Rhaenyra, father.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Rhaenyra.
(MUTTERING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
"The Song of Ice and Fire."
Do you believe it to be true?
Aegon's Dream.
You told me
it was our duty to hold
the realm united against a common foe.
By naming me heir,
you divided the realm.
(VISERYS BREATHING HEAVILY)
I thought I wanted it.
But the burden is a heavy one.
(SOFTLY) It's too heavy.
My...
My only child.
If you wish me to bear it,
then defend me.
And my children.
(SIGHS)
(QUIETLY) It's...
(THUNDERING)
(VISERYS MURMURS)
(RHAENYRA SNIFFLES)
(CRYING)
(BELLS TOLLING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I want to have supper, Otto.
- It is the morning, Your Grace.
- Tonight.
The whole of my family...
are gathered at the Red Keep.
I want us... to dine together.
(GROANING)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
Bring milk of the poppy.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(QUIETLY) No.
Just arrange the supper.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Though it is the great
hope of this court
that Lord Corlys Velaryon
survive his wounds,
we gather here
with the grim task
of dealing with
the succession of Driftmark.
As Hand, I speak with
the King's voice on this
and all other matters.
The crown will now
hear the petitions.
Ser Vaemond of House Velaryon.
VAEMOND: My Queen.
My Lord Hand.
The history of our noble houses
extends beyond
the Seven Kingdoms
to the days of Old Valyria.
For as long
as House Targaryen has ruled the skies,
House Velaryon
has ruled the seas.
When the Doom fell on Valyria,
our houses became
the last of their kind.
Our forebearers
came to this new land,
knowing that were they to fail,
it would mean the end
to their bloodlines and their name.
I have spent my entire life
on Driftmark defending my brother's seat.
I am Lord Corlys's closest kin,
his own blood.
The true, unimpeachable blood of
House Velaryon runs through my veins.
As it does in my sons,
the offspring of Laenor Velaryon.
If you cared so much
about your house's blood, Ser Vaemond,
you would not be so bold as
to supplant its rightful heir.
No, you only speak for yourself
- and for your own ambition.
- You will have chance
to make
your own petition, Princess Rhaenyra.
Do Ser Vaemond
the courtesy of allowing his to be heard.
What do you know
of Velaryon blood, Princess?
I could cut my veins
and show it to you
and you still
wouldn't recognize it.
This is about the future
and survival of my house, not yours.
My Queen, my Lord Hand.
This is a matter of blood,
not ambition.
I place the continuation of the survival
of my house and my line above all.
I humbly put myself before you
as my brother's successor...
the Lord of Driftmark
and Lord of the Tides.
Thank you, Ser Vaemond.
Princess Rhaenyra,
you may now speak
for your son, Lucerys Velaryon.
If I am to grace this farce
with some answer,
I will start by reminding the court
that nearly 20 years ago, in this very...
King Viserys of House Targaryen,
the First of His Name,
King of the Andals,
and the Rhoynar,
and the First Men,
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms,
and Protector of the Realm.
(DARK, TRIUMPHANT MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I will sit the throne today.
Your Grace.
(GROANING)
I will be fine.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CROWN CLATTERS)
I said I'm fine.
- Ah...
- Come on.
(GROANING)
- Steady.
- (VISERYS GROANS)
(GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I must... admit... my confusion.
I do not understand
why petitions are being heard
over a settled succession.
The only one present...
who might offer keener insight
into Lord Corlys's wishes
is the Princess Rhaenys.
Indeed, Your Grace.
It was ever my husband's
will that Driftmark
pass through Ser Laenor
to his true born son...
Lucerys Velaryon.
His mind never changed.
Nor did my support of him.
As a matter of fact, the Princess
Rhaenyra has just informed me of her desire
to marry her sons Jace and Luke
to Lord Corlys's granddaughters,
Baela and Rhaena.
A proposal to which
I heartily agree.
VISERYS: Well... the matter is settled.
Again.
I hereby reaffirm
Prince Lucerys of House Velaryon
as heir to Driftmark,
the Driftwood Throne,
and the next Lord of the Tides.
(WHEEZING)
You break law...
and centuries of tradition
to install your daughter
as heir.
Yet you dare tell me...
who deserves to inherit
the name Velaryon.
No.
I will not allow it.
"Allow it"?
Do not forget yourself, Vaemond.
(SHOUTS)
That is no true Velaryon,
and certainly no nephew of mine.
Go to your chambers.
You have said enough.
Lucerys is
my true-born grandson.
And you...
are no more
than the second son
of Driftmark.
You... may run your house
as you see fit...
but you will not decide
the future of mine.
My house survived the Doom
and a thousand
tribulations besides.
And gods be damned...
I will not see it ended
on the account of this...
(SOFTLY) Say it.
Her children...
(SHOUTS) are bastards!
And she...
is...
a whore.
(CROWD GASPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I...
will have your tongue for that.
(ALL GASPING)
He can keep his tongue.
- (SHOUTS) Disarm him!
- No need.
(VISERYS GROANING)
- ALICENT: Call the maesters!
- Father?
- (GROANING)
- Please, my love. You must take something for the pain.
I will not cloud my mind.
I must put things right.
(GROANING)
(SOLEMN MUSIC PLAYING)
The body will be ready for its return
to Driftmark on the morrow, my lady.
You may wish to leave
the Silent Sisters to their work.
It is ill luck to look
upon the face of death.
The Stranger has visited me
more times than I can count, Grand Maester.
I assure you...
he cares little
whether my eyes are open or closed.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(DOOR OPENS)
How good it is...
to see you all tonight...
together.
- Prayer before we begin?
- Yes.
May the Mother smile down
on this gathering with love.
May the Smith mend the bonds
that have been broken for far too long.
And to Vaemond Velaryon,
may the gods give him rest.
This is an occasion
for celebration, it seems.
My grandsons, Jace and Luke,
will marry their cousins,
Baela and Rhaena,
further strengthening the bond
between our houses.
A toast to the young Princes...
- and their betrothed.
- Hear, hear!
Well done, Jace.
You'll finally get to lie with a woman.
Let us toast as well
Prince Lucerys...
the future Lord of the Tides.
Hear, hear.
You'll be great.
You do know how the act
is done, I assume?
At least in principle?
Where to put your cock
and all that.
Let it be, cousin.
You can play the jester
if you wish,
- but hold your tongue before my betrothed.
- Mm-hm.
(CUTLERY CLATTERS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
It both gladdens my heart
and fills me with sorrow
to see these faces
around the table.
The faces most dear
to me in all the world...
yet grown so distant
from each other...
in the years past.
(MASK THUDS)
My own face...
is no longer a handsome one...
if indeed it ever was.
But tonight...
I wish you to see me... as I am.
Not just a king...
but your father.
Your brother.
Your husband...
and your grand sire.
Who may not, it seems...
walk for much longer among you.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (MASK CLANKS)
Let us no longer hold
ill feelings in our hearts.
The crown cannot stand strong
if the House of the Dragon
remains divided.
But set aside your grievances.
If not for the sake
of the crown...
then for the sake
of this old man
who loves you all
so dearly.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MASK CLANKING)
I wish to raise my cup
to Her Grace, the Queen.
I love my father.
But I must admit
that no one has stood...
more loyally by his side
than his good wife.
(POIGNANT MUSIC PLAYING)
She has tended to him with...
unfailing devotion,
love, and honor.
And for that,
she has my gratitude...
and my apology.
Your graciousness
moves me deeply, Princess.
We are both mothers...
and we love our children.
We have more in common
than we sometimes allow.
I raise my cup to you...
and to your house.
You will make a fine queen.
(PRINCE AEGON CLEARS THROAT)
I, um...
I regret the disappointment
you are soon to suffer.
But if you ever wish to know
what it is to be well satisfied,
all you have to do is ask.
Jace.
(PRINCE JACAERYS CLEARS THROAT)
To Prince Aegon and...
Prince Aemond.
We have not seen
each other in years,
but I have fond memories
of our shared youth.
And as men, I hope we may
yet be friends and allies.
To you and your family's
good health, dear uncles.
To you as well.
(SOFTLY)
Beware the beast beneath the boards.
Well done, my boy.
I would like to toast
to Baela and Rhaena.
They'll be married soon.
It isn't so bad.
Mostly he just ignores you...
except sometimes
when he's drunk.
(SCATTERED LAUGHTER)
- (WHISPERS) Good.
- Let us have some music.
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Excuse me.
(LAUGHING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(EMOTIONAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
- ALICENT: Guards.
- (VISERYS GROANING)
Please, sit down.
(PIG SIZZLING)
(CHUCKLES)
(HITS TABLE, MUSIC STOPS)
Final tribute.
To the health of my nephews:
Jace...
Luke...
and Joffrey.
Each of them handsome, wise...
hm...
- strong.
- Aemond.
PRINCE AEMOND: Come...
let us drain our cups
to these three...
- Strong boys.
- I dare you to say that again.
Why? 'Twas only a compliment.
Do you not think
yourself Strong?
- RHAENYRA: Jace!
- ALICENT: That is enough!
(GRUNTS)
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTING)
Why would you
say such a thing before these people?
I was merely expressing
how proud I am of my family, Mother.
Mm, though it seems
my nephews aren't quite as proud of theirs.
DAEMON: Wait, wait!
RHAENYRA: Go to your quarters.
All of you go, now.
(SIGHS)
(FOOTSTEPS RETREATING)
Mm.
Rhaenyra.
It's best, I think, if we
go back to Dragons tone.
You've only just arrived.
Let me see the children home.
I'll, um...
return on dragon back.
The King and I
would both like that.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOG BARKING)
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
It's been quite a night
at the castle, it seems.
Yes, my lady.
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
- (VISERYS GROANING)
Come on, come on.
- That's it.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
Oh...
Well done.
- I'm sorry.
- Shh.
- Shh, shh, shh.
But you wanted to know...
if I believe it to be true.
Believe what to be true,
my King?
Don't you remember?
Aegon...
Our son?
His Dream.
The Song of Ice...
and Fi...
It is true.
What he saw in the North.
The Prince That Was Promised.
I don't understand, Viserys.
(SIGHS)
The Prince.
Prince Aegon?
To unite the realm
against the cold...
and the dark.
It is you.
You are the one.
You must do this.
(SOFTLY) You must do this.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Shh, shh.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(BLOWS OUT CANDLE)
I understand, my King.
(GROANING)
(SOFTLY) No more.
No more.
(SHORT BREATHS)
My love.
(BREATHING STOPS)